this lecture is going to introduce the
本讲座将介绍
idea of mixed strategies and extend our
混合策略的想法并扩展我们的
previous concept of Nash equilibrium to
纳什均衡的先前概念
this new definition let's begin by
这个新定义让我们开始
looking at the matching pennies game
看配套的便士游戏
recall that it would be a pretty bad
回想起来那将是非常糟糕的
idea to play any deterministic strategy
发挥任何确定性策略的想法
in this game for example if player two
在这个游戏中，例如，如果玩家2
were to play heads then player one would
玩头，然后玩家一会
want to respond by playing heads to get
想要通过努力获得回应
a payoff of one meaning that player two
收益为一意味着第二个玩家
would prefer to change details so that
希望更改详细信息，以便
he can get this payoff of 1 meaning that
他可以获得1的收益
player 1 would prefer to change to tails
玩家1希望改成尾巴
so he can get this payoff of 1 meaning
所以他可以获得1的收益
that player 2 would prefer to change
该玩家2希望更改
back to heads to get this payoff of 1
回到头来获得1的收益
meaning that player 1 would prefer to
表示玩家1更愿意
change back to heads as well to get this
换回头来得到这个
payoff of 1 where we started and so you
我们开始的1的回报，所以您
can see there is kind of a cycle where
可以看到有一个循环
we just bounced around between the
我们只是在
different cells of this game matrix and
此游戏矩阵的不同单元格以及
essentially argued that no pair of
本质上说，没有一对
deterministic strategies works for both
确定性策略对两者都有效
players so what does work for both
玩家，那么什么对双方都有效
players well essentially it does make
玩家基本上可以做到
sense for players to confuse each other
玩家相互混淆的感觉
by choosing to play randomly so
通过选择随机播放
intuitively instead of saying I'm going
凭直觉而不是说我要去
to commit to playing heads or I'm going
致力于发挥作用，否则我要走了
to commit to playing tails I can say I'm
致力于打尾巴，我可以说我
going to commit to flipping this coin
打算投掷这枚硬币
and playing whatever side comes up so
并发挥任何方面，所以
let's try to make this idea formal
让我们尝试使这个想法正式化
before we talked about the idea of pure
在我们谈论纯粹的想法之前
strategies which we just equated to
我们刚才等同的策略
playing actions now let's think of
现在让我们想起玩游戏
things in terms of probability
事物的概率
distributions so let's say that a
分布，所以说
strategy for an agent is any probability
代理商的策略是任何可能性
distribution over the actions that the
分布在
player has available to him and a pure
玩家可以使用他的纯
strategy then is the special case where
策略就是特殊情况
I play only one action with positive
我只打一个积极的动作
probability a mixed strategy says I'm
混合策略说我很可能
just going to play more than one action
只是要玩多个动作
with positive probability there there
那里的可能性很大
might be a couple of different actions
可能是几个不同的动作
that I assign positive probability
我分配正概率
like in my example with matching pennies
就像在我的例子中一样
I'm going to call the support of my
我要打电话给我的支持
mixed strategy the set of actions that
混合策略
get positive probability so for example
得到正概率，例如
when I flip a coin when I'm playing
当我玩游戏时抛硬币
matching pennies both heads and tails
匹配头和尾的便士
are in the support of my mixed strategy
支持我的混合策略
my support is the set heads tails I'm
我的支持是固定的尾巴
going to define the set of all
要定义所有的集合
strategies for an agent I to be capital
代理人我成为资本的策略
S sub I and I'm going to define the set
S sub I，我要定义集合
of all strategy profiles capital S to be
所有策略配置文件中的资本S
the Cartesian product of these strategy
这些策略的笛卡尔积
sets for the different agents now I have
为不同的代理商设置了
the problem that I've elaborated my
我阐述了我的问题
definition of strategies in the game to
游戏中策略的定义
include not just this finite set of
不仅包括这个有限的
things players can do but this infinite
玩家可以做的事情，但是无限
set of all of the probability
所有概率的集合
distributions over these finite sets the
这些有限集的分布
reason this is a problem is I only have
原因是我只有
a utility definition for action profiles
动作配置文件的实用程序定义
and now I'm allowing things to happen
现在我允许事情发生
that I don't have utilities for that is
我没有实用程序是
to say I can't just read a number out of
说我不能只读一个数字
the game matrix to figure out how happy
游戏矩阵来找出幸福感
the players are when something happens
玩家在发生某事时
because under a mixed strategy with
因为在混合策略下
support of size greater than one I won't
支持的尺寸大于我不会的尺寸
always end up in the same cell of the
总是以相同的单元格结束
matrix so I can extend my definition of
矩阵，所以我可以扩展我的定义
utility here by leveraging the idea of
通过利用
expected utility from decision theory so
决策理论的预期效用
these equations explain what this means
这些等式解释了这意味着什么
it looks a lot more complicated than it
它看起来比它复杂得多
is
是
so what I'm saying here is that i's
所以我在这里说的是
utility under mixed strategy profile s
混合策略配置文件下的效用
where little s is some element of the
其中小s是
set of all possible mixed strategy
所有可能的混合策略的集合
profiles bigass is equal to the sum over
轮廓bigass等于总和
all action profiles in the game you can
您可以在游戏中的所有动作配置文件
kind of think of this intuitively as the
直觉上认为这是
sum over all of the cells in the normal
正常中所有单元的总和
form of the game where I take the
我参加的比赛形式
utility
效用
of each cell and I multiply it by the
的每个单元格，我乘以
probability that that cell will be
该单元格将成为的概率
reached in the given mixed strategy the
在给定的混合策略中达到
probability of getting two cell a
获得两个像元的概率
strategy profile a as a reaction profile
策略配置文件a作为反应配置文件
a given strategy profile else and then
给定的策略配置文件，然后
of course I need to define what this
当然，我需要定义什么
probability actually is and that's given
概率实际上就是这样
here the probability that I'll get to a
这是我到达
given action profile given a strategy
给定行动方案给定策略
profile S is just the product of the
配置文件S只是
probability of each player playing his
每个玩家玩他的概率
part of that action profile so in for
该操作资料的一部分，因此
example if this player was playing with
例如，如果该玩家正在玩
probability point five on each action
每个动作的概率点为5
and this player was playing with
和这个玩家一起玩
probability point five then the
概率点五然后
probability that I would get to this
我会做到这一点的可能性
cell is 0.25 this action profile arises
单元格为0.25，此操作配置文件出现
with probability 0.25 because this thing
概率为0.25，因为这件事
happens half the time and this thing
发生一半的时间，这件事
happens half the time and so we have to
发生一半的时间，所以我们必须
multiply those two probabilities
将这两个概率相乘
together to get the joint probability of
一起得到
this action profile so that's that's
这个动作资料，就是这样
what this definition here is saying so
这个定义在说什么
in total my utility for a strategy
总的来说，我的策略实用性
profile is my expected utility taking an
个人资料是我期望的实用程序
expectation over all of the action
对所有行动的期望
profiles in the support of that strategy
支持该策略的配置文件
profile and weighting each of them by
分别对它们进行配置并加权
the probability that that action profile
该动作描述的概率
would actually arise well now that I've
现在我已经可以很好地成长了
defined what strategies are I can go
确定我可以采取的策略
back to my definitions of best response
回到我对最佳回应的定义
and Nash equilibrium and basically they
和纳什均衡，基本上
work the way they did before except I
除了我之前，他们像以前一样工作
change all of the A's to asses so so
将所有A都更改为资产
that means I have to write these
这意味着我必须写这些
definitions again and I'll go through
再次定义，我将讲解
them again but conceptually if you
他们再次，但从概念上讲，如果你
understood what best response and Nash
了解什么是最佳反应，纳什
equilibrium meant in the case of actions
平衡意味着采取行动
then everything will work again so I
然后一切都会恢复正常，所以我
will say that a strategy s star I is an
会说我是策略明星
element of the set of best responses
最佳响应集的元素
to strategy profile s- i when the
到策略配置文件s- i
following condition is true for all
以下条件对所有人都适用
other strategies si the player I could
其他策略，我可以的球员
take for all of the strategies in the
采取所有策略
set of possible strategies for that
一套可行的策略
player notice that these this is an
玩家注意到这些是
infinite set but that's okay the
无限集，但是没关系
definition still works then the utility
定义仍然有效，然后实用程序
that the player would get for playing a
玩家会因为玩
star I when everybody else plays the
当其他人都扮演
strategy profile as minus I is at least
策略简介，我至少为负
as big as when he plays this other
和他玩这个游戏一样大
strategy si so let me say that again as
策略，所以我再说一遍
star I is a best response to strategy
明星我是对策略的最佳回应
profile s - I if it's at least as good
个人资料s-我至少是一样好
as anything else
和其他一样
given that everybody else is playing as
鉴于其他人都在玩
minus sign now we can say that a
减号现在我们可以说
strategy profile S is a Nash equilibrium
策略配置文件S是纳什均衡
if it's the case that for all agents
如果是这样的话，对于所有代理商
everybody is playing a best response
每个人都在做出最好的回应
incidentally you might notice that I'm
顺带一提，您可能会注意到我
using a set membership operator here
在这里使用设置的成员运算符
rather than an equal sign which is what
而不是等号
you might have expected to see well the
您可能期望看到的效果很好
reason I don't use an equal sign is
我不使用等号的原因是
because the set of best responses might
因为这组最佳响应可能
have more than one thing in it so the
其中不止一件事，所以
best there might not be only one best
最好可能不会只有一个最好的
response sometimes there'll be multiple
回应有时会有多个
best responses and so here what I'm
最好的回复，所以我在这里
saying is a strategy profile is one of
俗话说，策略简介是其中之一
the best responses if this condition is
如果这种情况是最好的响应
true and I'm saying a strategy profile
是的，我说的是战略概况
is a Nash equilibrium if everybody is
如果每个人都是纳什均衡
playing one of their best responses well
发挥最佳反应之一
this might seem like much ado about
这似乎很不值得
nothing I've introduced this idea of
我没有介绍过这个想法
randomizing as a strategy I've redefined
重新定义随机化策略
utility then I've leveraged this
实用程序，然后我利用了这个
redefined definition of utility which is
重新定义的实用程序定义是
incidentally what I'm using here when I
顺带一提，我在这里使用的是什么
talk about the utility of a strategy
谈论策略的效用
profile to define best response I've
配置文件以定义我的最佳响应
then leveraged that definition of best
然后利用最佳的定义
response here to talk about Nash
在这里回复谈论纳什
equilibrium and in total I've just ended
平衡，我刚结束
up kind of saying everything that you've
说出你所拥有的一切
already heard us say but what does
已经听到我们说了，但是怎么办
matter is that now that we have a new
重要的是，现在我们有了一个新
definition of Nash equilibrium were able
纳什均衡的定义能够
to state a theorem that we didn't have
陈述一个我们没有的定理
before and this is Nash's famous theorem
以前，这是纳什的著名定理
this is the reason why gets the Nash
这就是为什么得到纳什的原因
equilibrium named after him and this is
以他的名字命名的均衡，这是
one of the main reasons why Nash got the
纳什得到的主要原因之一
Nobel Prize this theorem actually didn't
这个定理实际上没有得到诺贝尔奖
take very long to prove but it's a
需要很长时间才能证明，但这是一个
really important thing for game theory
对博弈论来说真的很重要
and the theorem is that every finite
定理是每个有限
game has a Nash equilibrium what's first
游戏有纳什均衡先
of all what is a finite game this sounds
听起来是什么有限游戏
like I'm hedging here but it's not much
就像我在这里对冲，但数量不多
of a hedge a finite game just means that
套期保值游戏的意思是
the game takes a finite amount of space
游戏占用有限的空间
to write down so it has a finite number
写下来，所以它有一个有限的数
of players it has a finite number of
的玩家数量有限
actions for every player and that means
每个玩家的动作，这意味着
it has a finite number of utility values
它具有有限数量的效用值
in the game because the number of
在游戏中，因为
utility values is determined by the
效用值由
number of players and the number of
玩家人数和人数
actions for each player so as long as
每个玩家的动作，只要
the game has a finite number of players
游戏中有有限数量的玩家
not just two players but any finite
不只是两个玩家，而是任何有限玩家
number of players and a finite number of
玩家数量和有限数量的
actions for each player not just two
每个玩家的行动不只是两个
actions but but maybe a very big game
动作，但也许是一个很大的游戏
then no matter what the payoff values
那么无论收益多少
are no matter what strategic situation
无论是什么战略形势
we're talking about here no matter what
无论如何我们在这里谈论
real-world interaction this is modeling
现实世界中的互动，这是建模
there's going to be at least one Nash
至少会有一个纳什
equilibrium in this game that's a pretty
这个游戏的平衡点很漂亮
deep thing that's saying there will
那深深的意思是说
always be some stable thing that all of
始终是一些稳定的东西
the players can do which has the
玩家可以做到的
property that if they knew what everyone
属性，如果他们知道每个人
was doing none of them would want to
当时他们都不愿意
change their strategy that that's
改变他们的策略
basically one of the main reasons why we
基本上是我们为什么的主要原因之一
care about this idea of Nash equilibrium
关心纳什均衡的想法
because we know that no matter what the
因为我们知道无论
game is we can find such a Nash
游戏是我们可以找到这样的纳什
equilibrium and reason about it that's
平衡及其原因是
why Nash equilibrium is such a powerful
为什么纳什均衡如此强大
thing and that's only true when we have
事情，只有当我们有
this fuller definition of Nash
纳什的完整定义
equilibrium here that we've just defined
我们刚刚定义的均衡
in terms of strategies
在策略上
we saw that when we talked about Nash
当我们谈论纳什时，我们看到了
equilibrium in terms of just actions
公正行动方面的均衡
before what will now from this point on
从现在开始之前
refer to as pure strategy Nash
称为纯策略纳什
equilibrium so pure strategy Nash is
均衡，所以纯策略Nash是
when we do all of this with aids instead
当我们用辅助工具完成所有这些工作时
of s is that's a pure strategy Nash
的是纯策略Nash
equilibrium and the sad thing about that
平衡和可悲的是
is that we don't get a theorem that says
是我们没有定理说
that every finite game has one of those
每个有限的游戏都有其中一个
but this mixed strategy Nash equilibrium
但是这种混合策略纳什均衡
always exists let's do some examples
永远存在，让我们做一些例子
so remember matching pennies well we
所以记得很好地匹配便士
just argued at the beginning of this
刚在这开始争论
video effectively that matching pennies
视频有效匹配便士
doesn't have a pure strategy Nash
没有纯粹的策略纳什
equilibrium but it does have a mixed
平衡，但确实有混合
strategy Nash equilibrium it has one and
战略纳什均衡，它有一个
that is as I suggested before for both
正如我之前对两个建议一样
players to randomize 5050 and that
玩家随机分配5050
doesn't mean that it always has to be
并不意味着它总是必须
50/50 that just happens to be what the
50/50恰好是
Nash equilibrium is here that comes from
纳什均衡在这里来自
the symmetry of the payoffs but that
收益的对称性，但是
turns out to be the Nash equilibrium
原来是纳什均衡
here let's come back to the coordination
在这里，让我们回到协调
game well we've previously seen that
游戏不错，我们以前见过
these two strategy profiles I'm circling
我正在盘旋的这两个策略简介
outcomes but remember an outcome isn't
结果，但要记住不是
an equilibrium you know one one isn't
你知道一个平衡不是一个平衡
the equilibrium that would be wrong to
平衡是错误的
say the right thing to say is that left
说正确的话就是离开
left is in equilibrium right right is an
左侧处于平衡状态，右侧是
equilibrium but it turns out there's
平衡，但事实证明
another equilibrium here so it turns out
这里的另一个平衡
again 0.5 0.5 is a Nash equilibrium here
同样0.5 0.5是纳什均衡
as well and that's kind of funny because
同样，这很有趣，因为
it doesn't seem like point 5.5 is such a
似乎5.5点不是这样的
good thing to play in this game but you
在这个游戏中玩是一件好事，但是你
can confirm to yourself that if player 1
可以向自己确认如果玩家1
is randomizing by playing 50/50 then
通过玩50/50随机
player 2 can do no better than to
玩家2做不到
randomize 50/50 now you'll notice that
现在将50/50随机化，您会注意到
player 2 could do just as well by
玩家2可以做得很好
playing something else if player 1 is
如果玩家1在玩其他游戏
playing 50/50 player 1 is just as happy
玩50/50的玩家1同样开心
to go left all the time
一直走
but in particular player 1 if player 1
但特别是玩家1（如果玩家1）
is going 50/50 player 2 can do no better
即将进行50/50的玩家2做不到
than to go 50/50 himself the reverse is
比自己去50/50相反
also true
也是如此
and that makes 5050 5050 a Nash
那使得5050 5050成为纳什
equilibrium of the coordination game as
协调博弈的均衡为
well and let's look at prisoner's
好吧，让我们看看囚犯的
dilemma in prisoner's dilemma we've
我们在囚徒困境中的困境
previously seen that this is an
以前看到这是一个
equilibrium and it's an equilibrium in
平衡，这是一个平衡
strictly dominant strategies and we
严格的主导策略，我们
argued before the equilibria and
在平衡之前争论
strictly dominant strategies are unique
严格的主导策略是独特的
and so what that means is indeed there
所以那的确存在
aren't any mixed Nash equilibria of the
没有任何混合的纳什均衡
prisoner's dilemma this is in fact the
囚徒困境实际上是
only Nash equilibrium
只有纳什均衡